<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Celeste&#39;s R Blog</title>
    <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Celeste&#39;s R Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parallax Reflection</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_reflection/</guid>
      <description>An overview of my parallax experience I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past month or so working with LANDFIRE&amp;rsquo;s national data of area burned in the continental US prior to European colonization. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating dataset and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about different chart types, how to make maps, and other valuable skills. My goal from the beginning was to format the charts and text into a parallax, which is a neat style of scrolling document that I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed on this blog before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates and New Maps</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/updates_and_the_new_year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/updates_and_the_new_year/</guid>
      <description>First post of 2021! Today I wanted to share some updates on old maps, talk about my projects and goals in the spirit of the New Year, and show what I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.
After I sent Randy my map from Hexbin Maps and Choropleths, he fixed it up a bit and here is the final version.
Definitely looks a lot better, and I hope to keep improving.
As for the my leaRning goals (stole that from Randy) for this year, here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet of what I was thinking:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes to Self</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/notes_to_self/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/notes_to_self/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple things to check for if/ when I&amp;rsquo;m having R trouble. This is certainly not an exhaustive list and it only includes issues I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, but I hope this will be a productive way to keep track of things I run into time and time again.
When referencing files doesn&amp;rsquo;t work
 Set the working directory to the main folder and try again.  setwd()  Check spelling!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hexbin Maps and Choropleths</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/hexbin_maps_and_choropleths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/hexbin_maps_and_choropleths/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in a little while, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on choropleths! I hit a wall with some Mac-update related issues but luckily Randy was able to help me out and I seem to be past those.
Today I made my very first (successful) choropleth, which was a hexbin map of the continental United States, using data from the LANDFIRE Team of historical fire prevalence state-by-state and the overall acres burned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Parallax Scroll Document</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_testing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on my third try to make a parallax scroll document for national fire disturbance data. I had some file management issues with the first two but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out generally how it works.
I&amp;rsquo;m following Martin Chan&amp;rsquo;s tutorial and he uses the package parallaxr.
The parallax actually seems pretty simple with the package, but I have to make charts and maps in their own HTMLs, which may take a little bit more manuvering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First R Post on the Cleaned Blog!</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/first_r_post_on_cleaned_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/first_r_post_on_cleaned_blog/</guid>
      <description>Welcome welcome! I actually made a blog with a pretty theme! Thanks to J Pescador, who created this theme. This is actually my third try, since the first blog was forked from Crump Lab, the second was a different version of future imperfect and this is the third (and hopefully final) try! I created this during a conservation data lab (CDL) meeting.
Trying out pictures Earth Data Science gave me very helpful information on how to put in a picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing graphs and things</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/fixing_graphs_and_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/fixing_graphs_and_things/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since I blogged and I created some graphs! Today I&amp;rsquo;m just cleaning them up and fixing issues, like bunched-up letters or skinny lines.
I learned more about R bar graphs, which was nice because I&amp;rsquo;ve been using them without really understanding what they do. I still don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand each piece, but I figured out enough to insert the line
width=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; into my ggplot2 graph. I tried changing the theme, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work and said it couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about NE Fire Disturbance</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/thinking_about_ne_fire_disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/thinking_about_ne_fire_disturbance/</guid>
      <description>Things that might be interesting to cover
On the MSU Natural Features website, I was reading about the different types of forests and their disturbance patterns, and one thing that stuck out to me is that while temperature/ water access and other climate features impact the type of forest and therefore the fire prevalence, the fire prevalence also impacts the type of forest. For example, in the Dry-Mesic Southern forests, &amp;ldquo;historically, frequent, low-intensity surface fires generated conditions suitable for sustaining advanced oak regeneration and helped keep oak pathogens and invertebrate acorn predators at low levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Through the Basics</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/working_through_the_basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/working_through_the_basics/</guid>
      <description>Back into R! I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty busy but I&amp;rsquo;m going to work on figuring this all out. Randy shared a cleaned up version of the LANDFIRE Repository and very kindly explained what all of the labels mean. It looks like a really cool dataset! I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get into it.
I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to set this blog up and figure out how to do more practical things in R. I copied a line from Randy&amp;rsquo;s code and made this &amp;lsquo;journal&amp;rsquo; theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very first intro to R</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/very_first_intro_into_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/very_first_intro_into_r/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(message=FALSE,warning=FALSE, cache=TRUE) Introduction to R I began learning R using the SWIRL package over the summer. Now I want to try more data work for the Nature Conservancy and the Conservation Data Lab.
Testing out my own dataframe I wanted to make a data set to mess around with, so I made up some data about my friends&#39; family since they have a lot of kids and a lot of dogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
