<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Celeste&#39;s R Blog</title>
    <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Celeste&#39;s R Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Parallax Scroll Document</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/parallax_testing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on my third try to make a parallax scroll document for national fire disturbance data. I had some file management issues with the first two but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out generally how it works.
I&amp;rsquo;m following Martin Chan&amp;rsquo;s tutorial and he uses the package parallaxr.
The parallax actually seems pretty simple with the package, but I have to make charts and maps in their own HTMLs, which may take a little bit more manuvering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing graphs and things</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/fixing_graphs_and_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/fixing_graphs_and_things/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since I blogged and I created some graphs! Today I&amp;rsquo;m just cleaning them up and fixing issues, like bunched-up letters or skinny lines.
I learned more about R bar graphs, which was nice because I&amp;rsquo;ve been using them without really understanding what they do. I still don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand each piece, but I figured out enough to insert the line
width=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; into my ggplot2 graph. I tried changing the theme, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work and said it couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very first intro to R</title>
      <link>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/very_first_intro_into_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celestesrblog.netlify.app/blog/very_first_intro_into_r/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(message=FALSE,warning=FALSE, cache=TRUE) Introduction to R I began learning R using the SWIRL package over the summer. Now I want to try more data work for the Nature Conservancy and the Conservation Data Lab.
Testing out my own dataframe I wanted to make a data set to mess around with, so I made up some data about my friends&#39; family since they have a lot of kids and a lot of dogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
